[MUSIC]
مرحبا بكم بالسلسة التعليمية لجامعة امباير
سوف نستكشف معلومات
عن فيروس كورونا المستحدث
انا  هنا مع هيلين وارد
البروفيسور في قسم
وبائية الامراض المعدية .
اذن يا هيلين ,
هنالك  كميات معلومات هائلة
هناك في المجال العام
ماذا اضفنا نحن للمجال ؟
>> حسنا
ما سوف تكتشفين و تسمعين
من عندنا هو علم يقوم
على التقارير التي تجمع عن الوباء
هنا في جامعة امبريال , نملك مركز
متخصص في نمذجة العدوى
الناشئة و سوف تسمعين من فريق
المركز عن اخر التطورات حول
انتقال فيروس الكورونا
بروفيسور (نيل فيرغسون ) سوف يتحدث
اليك حول اهمية ( رقم التكاثر
الاساسي ) و تحديات الخطورة
المتوقعة للمرض
>> نعم
و الخبراء في الكليات و الاقسام
الاخرى هنا يشتركون من عدة
جوانب في البحث عن فيروس الكورونا
ليزودوا فرق الاستجابة حول
العالم بارشادات احترافية
Throughout this series of lessons,
you'll receive insights and
updates about the current
outbreak including information
regarding more general features of
outbreak modeling and response.
We will also try to highlight how
important lessons learned from previous
outbreaks like SARS and
Ebola might contribute to the fight.
>> One area that I'm keen to talk
to you about is the community
engagement which was a key lesson of
previous outbreaks such as Ebola.
This is a fast paced and
a rapidly changing situation.
So we will be updating this material
regularly including adding additional
content on the economic
impacts of the outbreak and
the vaccine development for example.
So, please keep coming back if you're
interested in learning more about
the science and staying current on
the latest information on Covo-19.
[MUSIC]